[♪ ominous music playing]
[growls]
[both grunting]
[grunting]
[yells]
[grunts]
[yelling]
-[grunts]
-[slashes]
[GOWTAN] Rock Shatterer!
[Ghoul Head groaning]
-[Gowtan gasps]
-[Wights snarling]
[grunts]
-[gasps]
-[growls]
[chomping]
[growls]
[grunts]
[Teal, Paul gasp]
-[Ghoul Head growls]
-[Gowtan gasps]
[growls]
[all whimpering]
[Ghoul Head growling]
[both whimpering]
[chomping]
[grunts]
[roaring]
[all gasp]
Could it be?
It may have healed,
but at least now all those
damnable Wights are gone.
[grunts]
Gowtan, stop!
Get away from that thing!
[Gowtan grunts] I'll settle this
once and for all!
[roars]
[all straining]
[both whimpering]
[gasps]
[roaring]
[grunting]
[roars]
[all whimpering]
[both whimpering]
[growls]
[AUTOMATED VOICE] Ghoul Head
has evolved into Mad Headder.
Level 40 has been reached.
[ELYMAS] I can't believe it.
The Ghoul Head's already risen
to Gowtan's level?
[laughing]
Uh, what just happened?
[grunts] This is bad.
[♪ opening theme song playing]
BEGIN ADVENTURE
EPISODE 4 EXISTENCE EVOLUTION
[Mad Headder growling]
[all whimpering]
[both whimpering]
[gasps]
[breathing heavily]
[ELYMAS] Existence Evolution.
A rare event that occurs
when certain conditions are met.
TAKE THIS!
It primarily refers to monsters
awakening latent abilities
and transforming
into another species altogether
to escape sticky situations.
BUFF - WHAT? - NO WAY!
Even in Magic World,
the exact conditions
for Existence Evolution
weren't very clear.
But I know this much.
Things have taken a huge turn
for the worse.
[gasps]
Gowtan! Don't stand there!
[grunts]
[groans]
[AUTOMATED VOICE]
Status Effect. Stunned.
-Teal! Paul!
-[both gasp]
Go distract the big guy!
What is it you expect us to do?
If I attack using magic,
that thing will kill me so fast,
I won't know what happened!
[grunts]
But if Gowtan goes down,
every last one of us will die!
-We can't let that happen!
-[roars]
[grunts]
[groans]
[Gowtan yells]
[gasps]
[both whimpering]
[grunts]
[groaning]
[AUTOMATED VOICE]
Status Effect. Paralysis.
[both gasp]
-[groaning]
-[Mad Headder growls]
[roars]
-[both whimpering]
-[grunts]
[both grunt]
[breathes deeply]
[both whimper]
-[ELYMAS] I'll distract it!
-[both gasp]
Meanwhile, you get Gowtan,
then cast
Heal and Paralysis Heal on him.
You hear me, Teal?!
I haven't upgraded
to Paralysis Heal.
I used up all my skill points
to increase my attack!
So I can't cure him!
[ELYMAS] Is he serious?
[grunts] What kind of
half-assed build is that?
[ELYMAS] Either way,
you should take Gowtan
to a safe place
and heal his wounds!
-Now move!
-Right!
-[panting]
-[grunts]
[ELYMAS]
When they're hit directly,
most people recover
from Mad Headder's poison
after three minutes on average.
If I can survive that long...
[panting heavily]
...Teal will have Gowtan back
in the fight with us.
[TEAL] Heal.
[ELYMAS] One thing's for sure,
I didn't know that reality
would be so different
from the game.
MONSTER: MAD HEADDER
[gasps]
[grunts] I'll fight you,
Mad Headder,
until Gowtan rallies.
So let's do this!
[growls]
-[all whimpering]
-[ADVENTURER 1] What?
An F-rank adventurer can't go up
against a monster like that.
-He'll be torn apart!
-You fool!
We should run
while we still can!
Once that thing kills him,
we'll be next!
-Hey, slow down. Wait for me!
-[all gasp]
[ELYMAS] That's fine.
If they joined the fray,
they wouldn't last 10 seconds.
I can't afford to defend
low-level adventurers
while I'm trying
to fight this thing
-single-handedly.
-[whimpers]
-[Gowtan groaning]
-[Teal whimpering]
[roaring]
[gasps]
[ELYMAS] I'm Level 16 now.
But the Mad Headder
is already up to Level 40.
Even one mistake,
and I'll be dead!
[Mad Headder grunting]
[electricity crackling]
-[roars]
-[gasps]
[grunts]
[growls]
[Elymas panting]
[panting]
[growls]
[stone clattering]
[grunts]
[♪ intense music playing]
[gasps]
[growls]
[Elymas grunts]
[roars]
[Mad Headder grunts]
[Elymas yelling]
[grunting]
[all gasp]
[ELYMAS] Our level difference
is too great.
This blows.
I never thought
I'd be facing down
such a powerful opponent
unprepared.
I wanted to avoid a situation
like this.
It's high-risk, high-return.
I feel like the limits
of my abilities
are being put to the test.
It's definitely got
my blood pumping!
[grunts]
[panting]
-[Elymas grunts]
-[gasps]
Oh, wow.
Is this Heavy Knight
actually holding his own
against the same monster
that sent Mr. Gowtan flying off
-head-over-heels?
-Idiot. He's slowly losing.
It's a miracle
-he's not dead yet.
-[grunts]
-[roars]
[Mad Headder growls]
[ELYMAS] If I just keep allowing
the Mad Headder
to attack me like that,
it's going to land
a blow eventually.
I've got to think.
There must be something else
I can do.
REMAINING SKILL POINTS: 5
[AUTOMATED VOICE]
Beginner Swordsmanship
has reached Level Five.
Vital Slice Skill
has been acquired.
Skill, Vital Slice.
Land a heavy blow with a blade
from zero distance.
Effective against targets
with high defense.
Right!
[roars]
[ELYMAS] Parry! [grunts]
[grunting]
[grunts]
Vital Slice!
-[grunts]
-[both gasp]
[grunts]
[sighs]
[Mad Headder growls]
[growls]
[both whimpering]
[sighs]
[ELYMAS] Vital Slice sacrifices
the blade's reach.
-So it was considered subpar.
-[growls]
-[all whimpering]
- But its effectiveness
at dealing damage
works perfectly for low-attack,
high-defense builds.
Like for Heavy Knights.
However, that alone
won't be enough to defeat it.
[roars]
[both grunting]
It's attacking wildly!
[roaring]
Don't you worry, Mad Headder,
because now the real battle's
about to begin!
-But...
-[growls]
...I'm afraid my job is done.
-[Gowtan yells]
[all gasp]
[chuckles smugly]
[roars]
[both grunt]
It's attacking wildly!
[roaring]
Don't you worry, Mad Headder,
because now the real battle's
about to begin.
-But...
-[growls]
...I'm afraid my job is done.
-[Gowtan yells]
[all gasp]
[chuckles smugly]
[Gowtan grunts]
[yells]
[Mad Headder groans]
[GOWTAN] Dragonslayer Split!
[groaning]
[crashes]
[Gowtan panting]
-Yeah!
-All right!
-[all laughing]
-[chuckles softly]
[cape rustling]
[sighs]
[AUTOMATED VOICE]
Level has increased
from Level 16 to 23.
[GOWTAN] Hmm.
A mere F-rank adventurer
managed to survive
after going up
against a monster
that nearly killed me?
I just reached my limit.
So thank you, Gowtan.
[growls]
[all gasp]
[♪ tense music playing]
Hmm.
[inhales deeply]
-Forgive me, Elymas!
-[gasps]
I'm sorry.
I've been an incompetent leader,
and you were absolutely right
about everything.
[ELYMAS] Gowtan?
[GOWTAN]
I think you should take that.
[ELYMAS] A Level 40 Magic Stone?
Bet it's pretty valuable.
I'm so broke,
I'd be more than happy
to take it.
You sure?
Hmm. You're the adventurer
who destroyed that monster.
Hmm?
[gasps] Hmm.
It seems that
along with the stone,
this thing
dropped an item as well.
Do you want to take that one?
Huh?
[grunts] Of course not.
You killed the beast,
and I'm not someone
who goes back on his word.
[groans]
Uh...
But could I just have a look
at the item description?
-[all gasp]
-Yeah, sure.
[all gasp in awe]
[AUTOMATED VOICE]
Daemonsrage Shield.
Plus 25 defense.
Market price, 3 million gold.
After blocking an attack,
your next attack receives
a plus eight bonus.
[all gasp]
[ELYMAS] That thing
left a rare drop
worth 3 million gold?!
Rampart Reflection
only activates
when my armor's struck.
But with these kinds of stats,
I could shut down attacks
around my level
with just this shield!
Although,
if I sold something valuable,
it would attract a lot
of attention.
This is really 3 million gold,
huh? [grunts]
[ELYMAS] So, Gowtan...
About my promotion.
There's no need to worry.
I'll tell the guild
it'll be their loss
if they can't see your value
and move you up to rank E.
[all gasp]
And they'd better
do it right away.
Do you really mean that?
The guild said
I was to make sure
you didn't do
anything deceitful and cheat.
But their warning
was completely misguided.
[gasps]
So if anyone's foolish enough
to oppose your promotion,
I'll knock them out!
-Huh?
-[laughs boisterously]
[all laugh awkwardly]
Um. So, uh...
-Excuse me, Mr. Gowtan.
-Huh?
[TEAL] If it's all right,
I was wondering
if you'd approve my promotion
as well.
I mean, after all,
it was my Heal that got you back
to your feet, wasn't it?
-[GOWTAN] Teal!
-[gasps]
You lost your nerve
while facing down that monster
and let fear
get the better of you.
I think we both know
I would never approve
of such a thing.
In dungeons, you'll encounter
far greater challenges
than this one.
You should go train
with some quests you can handle!
[gasps]
[whimpering]
[sighs]
♪
[birds chirping]
[distant chatter]
And I let it slip
right through my fingers.
Aw, look at the two lovebirds.
[CRAFTSMAN] Not too bad, huh?
[laughing]
[indistinct chatter]
[RECEPTIONIST] Um...
I have your reward
for the raid here.
First off,
you'll receive 130,000 gold.
Huh?
-[RECEPTIONIST] In addition...
-[both gasp]
...you'll be receiving
200,000 gold
for 10 Wight Magic Stones.
[all gasp]
[RECEPTIONIST]
And as for the final item...
There's even more?
...we've calculated
the grand total
for the Mad Headder's
Magic Stone, and it's...
[grunts]
...600,000 gold.
[all gasp]
[laughs]
Looks like you actually made
more money than I did this time.
These raids are
pretty good money.
[ADVENTURER 1]
That’s a ton of gold.
[ADVENTURER 2] He made
even more than Mr. Gowtan?
[curious chatter]
Gowtan, sir. Um,
did this man really go up
against the Ghoul Head variant
and manage to take it down?
Hold on.
Didn't he raise some eyebrows
after bringing in high-level
Magic Stones before?
He's got to be using a trick.
What's his level anyway?
[ADVENTURER 3] Defense classes
are too weak.
[ADVENTURER 4] What do you have
to say about this, Mr. Gouton?
[receptionist whimpers
nervously]
[ADVENTURER 5] Yeah,
how could a defensive class
like Heavy Knight
ever kill that many monsters?
[Gowtan yells angrily]
How dare you doubt
Elymas's abilities!
I am the one
who approved his promotion,
so you're all
insulting me as well!
[all groan uneasily]
[growling]
[ELYMAS] Thanks for everything,
Gowtan.
-I appreciate it.
-Hmm.
Of course. Take care.
[ELYMAS]
If he hadn't stood up for me,
people would still be talking
behind my back.
And with his help,
I was promoted
from Rank F to Rank E.
[BOY 1] Sure!
[BOY 2] Like a real mission!
[laughing]
[indistinct chatter]
Hey. You wanna team up?
Nah. Thanks.
[ELYMAS]
So, what should I do now?
I've got to think this through.
Since I finally
leveled up to Rank E,
I can start entering dungeons
to farm gold.
But the Rampart Reflection
strat relies
on overwhelming defense.
So for now, it only works
when I'm up against
starter enemies.
And with the skill setup
I'm working with,
I'm pretty sure I'll be stuck
grinding levels for a while.
[birds chirping]
So for the moment,
to set my course,
maybe I should try
looking for that.
[gasps]
A Fang of Smoldering Insanity
skill book.
If I had one in my possession,
I'd be able to unlock
an entire skill tree.
They're extremely rare,
so I won't find one right away.
But looking for one is free.
REMAINING SKILL POINTS: 5
OATH OF THE HEAVY ARMOR
Oath of the Heavy Armor
and Fang of Smoldering Insanity.
These are two skill trees
that work together
to complete the Heavy Knight.
And when that happens,
the Heavy Knight is no longer
a defense specialist,
but referring to it
as an offense specialist
isn't right either.
At that point,
it becomes a human weapon.
If I want to move forward
and unlock my true potential,
Fang of Smoldering Insanity
is vital.
But...
[indistinct chatter]
[♪ closing theme song playing]
[ELYMAS] Though the battle
was hard-won,
I still managed to get promoted
to Rank E.
For me, the next step
couldn't be clearer.
I'll become a real Heavy Knight.
Not one known
as a defense specialist,
nor one who focuses on offense,
but as a warrior who fights
like a human weapon.
And to do that,
I have to find that skill book.
Next time,
"Fang of Smoldering Insanity."
Anyway, this problem
is shockingly expensive.